# Obi Anthony Uchenna

# **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

Megagigdev@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Portfolio

#### **SUMMARY**

As a Full Stack Web Developer with experience majorly in JavaScript, and Ruby on Rails, I have a track record of writing clean code and building user-friendly websites. My passion for open-source projects and remote work, including pair programming, and team leadership has contributed to my proficiency in various programming languages, frameworks, and technologies. My adaptability to new technologies is reflected in my ability to learn and implement them guickly.

#### SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind, React, Next.js, Redux

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Node. js, Express. js, Nest. js, Ruby, Rails

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Netlify, Chrome Dev Tools, Gitlab, Wix, WordPress, Weebly, OOP, TDD, Aws Kenisis,

Azure, WebRTC

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring, Professional Interpersonal relationships,

Professional Code reviews, Agile Methodologies

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Full Stack Web Developer

Remote February 2023 - Present

My journey through full-stack development has led me to master intermediate and advanced concepts, including the Git and GitHub workflow. I've honed this expertise through a myriad of solo and collaborative projects, giving me the chance to excel both independently and as part of a dynamic team.

**Cinema Cafe App** — A web app that showcases proper use of ES6 javascript syntax to hit an API in creating a highly scalable web app that displays information for current Movies and TV.

- Built with: JavaScript, HTML, CSS
- Visit Website: Cinema Cafe App

Bookstore CMS – Bookstore CMS is your ultimate tool for effortlessly managing your book collection.

- Built with: React, Redux, CSS3, Notion API)
- Visit website: <u>Bookstore CMS</u>

Calorie Tracker — A web App that helps to track nutrition, water, fitness, and weight loss goals.

- Built with: JavaScript, HTML, CSS3, Tailwind,
- Visit website: <u>Calorie Tracker</u>

Remote Job App —Remote Job App is a web application that allows users to search and apply for remote jobs from various companies around the world. It uses React for the front end, Redux for the state management, and Axios for fetching data from an external API.

- Built with: Javascript, React, Redux, COVID-19 API
- Visit website: Remote Job Web App

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) March 2023 – April 2023

Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.

- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on maintaining motivation including daily achievements or projects as well as positive feedback to maintain longevity in the program.

Tech A Intern

Remote

Full stack Developer (Intern)

October 2023 – December 2023

- Full stack Developer (Intern)Write Clean and scalable code for frontend in typescript React.
  - Integrate Real-time communication services with Node and Nestjs backend
  - Documentation and CI/CD pipeline processes, written and duly followed
  - Work with teams of different people globally with proper professionalism and conflict resolution

## **EDUCATION**

MICROVERSE February 2023 – Present

#### Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.